Finding Aid for the Frank Lawrence Owsley Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Professional Activities
  - Events
    - University of Kentucky—Blazer Lectures – “Self-Imposed Restraints and the Survival of American Democracy” given by Owsley, April 5, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - University of Mississippi---Lectures—Program November 1948 “Role of the Plain Folk in Ante-Bellum Southern History” and “Southern Folkways” given by Owsley (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - Vanderbilt University— Program--George Washington Lecture by William E. Dodd, February 22-24, 1932 (Box 9, Folder 38)
- Academic Career
  - Appointment and Salary letters (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper Articles (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Course syllabi, Exams, Bibliographies, etc. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Committee work, Oath of affirmation at Columbia University, Retirement Fund Receipt, Gift card from History Graduate students (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - University of Chicago—Transcript (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Lecture notes, class notes (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Lecture notes, class notes (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Lecture notes, class notes (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Lecture notes, class notes (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Vanderbilt University—Grade books (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - University of Alabama—Grade books (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - University of Alabama—Budget requests, 1953 – 1954 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Student papers—Larry M. Baker, “Civil War and Reconstruction” (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Student papers—Claude Bradshaw, “Civil War and Reconstruction: (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Student papers—Mary Joyce Ponder, “Civil War and Reconstruction” (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Student papers—Thomas Stricklin, “The United States and Neutral Rights, 1854 - 1856 (Box 10, Folder 16)
- Research Materials
  - King Cotton Diplomacy
    - Notecards
      - Adams, Charles F. (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Adams, Charles F. (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Agriculture (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Agriculture (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Agriculture (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - Arms and Munitions, U. S. Imports (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - Arms and Munitions, U.S. Imports (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - Arms and Munitions, U. S. Imports (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - Blockade (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - Blockade (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Blockade (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - Blockade (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - Blockade (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - Blockade (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - Blockade Running (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - Blockade Running (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - Blockade Running (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - Blockade Running (Box 12, Folder 9)
      - Blockade Running (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Blockade Running (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - Blockade Running (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - Blockade Running (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - Blockade Running (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - Blockade Running (Box 13, Folder 6)
      - Blockade Running (Box 13, Folder 7)
      - Blockade Running (Box 13, Folder 8)
      - Blockade Running (Box 13, Folder 9)
      - Blockade Running (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - Blockade Running (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - Britain, Danger of War with (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - Britain, Danger of War with (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - British Consuls in the Confederacy (Box 14, Folder 5)
      - British Consuls in the Confederacy (Box 14, Folder 6)
      - British Neutrality (Box 14, Folder 7)
      - Clay, Clement C. (Box 14, Folder 8)
      - Confederate Finances, February – July 1861 (Box 14, Folder 9)
      - Confederate Finances, July 1861 – January 1872 (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - Confederate Finances, January – December 1862 (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - Confederate Finances, December 1862 – May 1863 (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - Confederate Finances, May – July 1863 (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - Confederate Finances, July – October 1863 (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - Confederate Finances, October – December 1863 (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - Confederate Finances, December 1863 – April 1864 (Box 15, Folder 7)
      - Confederate Finances, April – September 1864 (Box 15, Folder 8)
      - Confederate Finances, October 1864 – February 1865 (Box 15, Folder 9)
      - Confederate Navy (Box 15, Folder 10)
      - Confederate Navy (Box 15, Folder 11)
      - Confederate Research Club (Box 15, Folder 12)
      - Dudley, Thomas H., Consul (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - Dudley, Thomas H. ,Consul (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - Morse, Freeman H., Consul (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - Morse, Freeman H., Consul (Box 16, Folder 4)
      - Morse, Freeman H., Consul (Box 16, Folder 5)
      - Cotton Famine (Box 16, Folder 6)
      - Cotton Famine (Box 16, Folder 7)
      - Destruction of American Merchant Marine (Box 16, Folder 8)
      - Diplomatic Communications (Box 16, Folder 9)
      - Diplomatic Communications (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - Diplomatic Communications (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - Diplomacy (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - Diplomacy (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - Diplomacy, England, U.S. (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - Diplomacy, Mason Papers (Box 17, Folder 6)
      - Diplomacy, Mason Papers (Box 17, Folder 7)
      - Diplomacy, Development of a Policy (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - Diplomacy, Mediation (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - Diplomacy (Box 17, Folder 10)
      - Diplomacy (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - Diplomacy (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - Diplomacy (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - Education (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - Education (Box 18, Folder 4)
      - Education (Box 18, Folder 5)
      - Freedom of the Seas, Admiral Charles Wilkes (Box 18, Folder 6)
      - History of Alabama (Box 18, Folder 7)
      - History of Alabama (Box 18, Folder 8)
      - Intervention, Mediation (Box 18, Folder 9)
      - Intervention, Mediation (Box 18, Folder 10)
      - Intervention, Mediation (Box 18, Folder 11)
      - Intervention, Mediation (Box 18, Folder 12)
      - Intervention for Cotton (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - Intervention for Cotton (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - Intervention for Wheat (Box 19, Folder 3)
      - Ironclads, U.S. and Great Britain (Box 19, Folder 4)
      - Ironclads, U.S. and Great Britain (Box 19, Folder 5)
      - Ironclads, U.S. and Great Britain (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - Ironclads, U.S. and Great Britain (Box 19, Folder 7)
      - Ironclads, France (Box 19, Folder 8)
      - Mercenaries (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - Mercenaries (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - Mercenaries (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - Mercenaries (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - Mercenaries (Box 20, Folder 5)
      - Mercenaries (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - Mercenaries (Box 20, Folder 7)
      - Mercenaries (Box 20, Folder 8)
      - Mercenaries (Box 20, Folder 9)
      - Mercenaries (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - Mercenaries (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - Mercenaries (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - Mistreatment of British Subjects—crews (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - Mistreatment of British Subjects—crews (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - Mistreatment of British Subjects—crews (Box 21, Folder 6)
      - Notecards (Box 21, Folder 7)
      - Notecards (Box 21, Folder 8)
      - Notecards (Box 21, Folder 9)
      - Notecards (Box 21, Folder 10)
      - Notecards (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - Notecards (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - Notecards (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - Notecards (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - Notecards (Box 22, Folder 5)
      - Notecards (Box 22, Folder 6)
      - Paris Negotiations (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - Patterns of Migration (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - Peacemakers of 1864 (Box 22, Folder 9)
      - Peacemakers of 1864 (Box 22, Folder 10)
      - Personalities—Napoleon, Lincoln, Jefferson Davis, others (Box 22, Folder 11)
      - Public Opinion (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - Public Opinion (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - Public Opinion, Hostility to U. S. (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - Public Opinion, Hostility to U.S. (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - Public Opinion, Hostility to U.S. (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - Public Opinion, Hostility to U.S. (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - Sanford, Henry Shelton (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - Sanford, Henry Shelton (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - Sanford, Henry Shelton (Box 24, Folder 1)
      - Sanford, Henry Shelton (Box 24, Folder 2)
      - Sanford, Henry Shelton (Box 24, Folder 3)
      - Sanford Papers, Surveillance (Box 24, Folder 4)
      - Sanford Papers, Surveillance (Box 24, Folder 5)
      - Seizure of British Commerce (Box 24, Folder 6)
      - Seizure of British Commerce (Box 24, Folder 7)
      - Seizure of British Commerce (Box 24, Folder 8)
      - Seizure of British Commerce (Box 24, Folder 9)
      - Seward, F.W. (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - Seward, F.W. (Box 25, Folder 2)
      - Seward, F.W. (Box 25, Folder 3)
      - Seward, William Henry (Box 25, Folder 4)
      - Seward, William Henry (Box 25, Folder 5)
      - Seward, William Henry (Box 25, Folder 6)
      - Seward, William Henry (Box 25, Folder 7)
      - Seward, William Henry (Box 25, Folder 8)
      - Seward, William Henry (Box 25, Folder 9)
      - Seward, William Henry (Box 25, Folder 10)
      - Seward, William Henry (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - Seward, William Henry (Box 26, Folder 2)
      - Slaveholders, Civil War (Box 26, Folder 3)
      - Slaveholders, Civil War (Box 26, Folder 4)
      - Slavery Issue (Box 26, Folder 5)
      - Slavery Issue (Box 26, Folder 6)
      - Surveillance (Box 26, Folder 7)
      - Surveillance (Box 26, Folder 8)
      - Surveillance (Box 26, Folder 9)
      - Surveillance—Other Vessels (Box 27, Folder 1)
      - Surveillance—Other Vessels (Box 27, Folder 2)
      - Surveillance—Other Vessels (Box 27, Folder 3)
      - Surveillance—U.S. and Great Britain, U. S. and France (Box 27, Folder 4)
      - Surveillance—U. S. and Great Britain, U.S. and France (Box 27, Folder 5)
      - Surveillance Funds (Box 27, Folder 6)
      - Surveillance Funds (Box 27, Folder 7)
      - Trade with the Enemy (Box 28, Folder 1)
      - Trade with the Enemy (Box 28, Folder 2)
      - Trent Affair (Box 28, Folder 3)
      - Trent Affair (Box 28, Folder 4)
      - U.S. and France, Procurement of Arms (Box 28, Folder 5)
      - U. S. and France and Great Britain Belligerent Rights (Box 28, Folder 6)
      - U.S. and France and Great Britain Belligerent Rights (Box 28, Folder 7)
      - U.S. and France and Great Britain Declaration of Paris (Box 28, Folder 8)
      - U.S. and France and Great Britain Declaration of Paris (Box 28, Folder 9)
      - U.S., France, and Mexico (Box 28, Folder 10)
      - U.S., France, and Mexico (Box 28, Folder 11)
      - U.S., France, and Mexico (Box 28, Folder 12)
      - U.S., France, Mexico (Box 29, Folder 1)
      - U.S., France, Mexico (Box 29, Folder 2)
      - U.S. and Mexico (Box 29, Folder 3)
      - U.S. and Mexico (Box 29, Folder 4)
      - U.S. and Mexico (Box 29, Folder 5)
      - U.S. and Mexico (Box 29, Folder 6)
      - U.S. and Mexico (Box 29, Folder 7)
      - Walker, John Williams (Box 29, Folder 8)
      - Walker, John Williams (Box 29, Folder 9)
      - Walker, John Williams (Box 30, Folder 1)
      - Walker, John Williams (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - Wills, Legal Documents (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Wills (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - Wills (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - Bibliography—Manuscript documents (Box 30, Folder 6)
      - Bibliography—Manuscript documents (Box 30, Folder 7)
      - Bibliography---Manuscript documents (Box 30, Folder 8)
      - Bibliography (Box 30, Folder 9)
      - List—Names of Foreign Ministers, Librarians, Consuls, etc. (Box 30, Folder 10)
FRANK OWSLEY - Incoming Correspondence: Some Significant Entries (based on index with notes compiled by Harriet C. Owsley)
ABERNEEHY, Thomas Perkins (12), 1935-53; professor of history, University of Virginia; comments on writings of agrarians and Owsley's historical writings.
AGAR, Herbert (4) 1935-36; re; plans for Who Owns America with enclosures of Ferris Greenslet (Houghton Mifflin Company) and Chard Powers Smith (who praises Land of the Free).
ALEXANDER, Thomas B. (39), 1942-56; these are good letters full of descriptions of England during and after V.E. day, opinions on politics and burning issues of the period. Anyone interested in World War II would find them valuable. Alexander was a naval officer. Other letters were written from places where he taught, including Clemson Agricultural College, Clemson, S. C., and Georgia Teachers College, Collegeboro, Georgia. He discusses writings and teaching problems. He received a Guggenheim Fellowship in 1955.
BANKHEAD, J. H. (2), 1935; re: "Pillars of Agrarianism" and proposed Bill to create farm tenant homes. Enclosed is a radio talk by Senator Bankhead on the subject.
BEACH, Leonard B. (2), 1954-55; re: collecting papers of Fugitives and Agrarians; also Waller project.
BEARD, Charles A. (6), 1940-45; re: Plain Folk of Old South; states that his family were of that class; compliments work on a neglected field of American history.
BEATTY, Richmond C. (4), 1934-50; re: ms. of Bayard Taylor -- if published, "it will just step up to you and call you Pappy"; compliments Plain Folk; especially chapter on Southern Folkways.
BINKLEY, William C. (13), 1931-54; re: graduate work at Vanderbilt (1930's); reorganized program; material in census (1937); Chancellor Kirkland's resignation and Carmichael as successor; Tennessee Historical Society (1937); athletic situation at Vanderbilt (1951); life in Huntsville, l880-95, subject for thesis; Joe Lehmann; move to Tulane; research projects (1954).
BLACK, Hugo L., 1935; re: Bankhead's bill for tenant farmer; tariff; and I'll Take My Stand.
BONDS, A. B., Jr., 1941; re: use of quotation from "Pillars of Agrarianism."
BORSODI, Ralph (2), 1937; re: tenant farmers and agrarianism.
BROOKS, Cleanth (7), 1934-39; re: writings and literary discussions, and proposed essays for Southern Review.
BROWN, C. K., 1937; re: regionalism and The American Review.
CARTER, Thomas H. (3), re: article on agrarians in the Shenandoah.
GAULEY, T. J. (2), 1935; re: Resettlement Administration and rural rehabilitation.
CHAMBERS, D. L. (2), 1936; re: Long Night by Andrew Lytle.
CHAPPELL, James E. (6), 1935-51; re: writings in American Review; Carmichael's situation at Vanderbilt, and other Vanderbilt problems of Board of Trust.
COUCH, W. T. (7); 1934-35; re: publication of student's historical writings; and agrarianism.
CRAVEN, Avery O. (14), 1933-56; re: historical writings, symposium for Dodd; reprints, etc.
DANIELS, Jonathan, 1936; re: "A Letter to the Yankees."
DAVIDSON, Donald (11), 1933-52; very fine letters about Agrarians and Fugitives.
DODD, William E. (4), 1931-35; re: King Cotton Diplomacy; articles in American Review; and agrarianism.
DYER, John Percy (26), 1934-50; re: writings, schools, agrarians, etc.
ENGLAND, Robert (2), 1935; re: proposed conference of Southern Editors; laments trouble with Virginia Quarterly; proposes new literary magazine.
FLETCHER, John Gould (12), 1933-35; re: agrarianism, boycott of Virginia Quarterly, writings, etc.
FORRESTER, Donal F. (2), 1933, 1934; re: comparison of agrarians with Belloc, Chesterton, et al.
GRAVES, John Temple, 1955; re: writings and I'II Take My Stand.
KUHLMAN, A. F. (3), 1942-43; re: proposal to establish Fugitive-Agrarian collection.
LYTLE, Andrew (28), 1934-56; re: The Long Night, agrarianism, and other writings.
MILLER, Francis P. (6); re: agrarianism, articles in American Review and Southern Review.
MOORE, Albert Burton (93), 1917-55; re: schools, writings, football, politics, University of Alabama, teaching positions, graduate program, etc.
NIXON, H. C. (24), 1926-56; re: experiences in Europe; politics and FDR; farm tenancy; Pillars of Agrarianism; refusal to write for Who Owns America; ideas on textbook.
ODUM, Howard (2), 1938, 1940; re: "poor whites" and article on Economic Basis of Society.
RAWE, John C., S. J., 1937; re: farm tenancy and agrarianism.
SHRYOCK, Richard H. (3), 1936-40; re: grants and writings on Southern history.
SILVER, James W. (12), 1936-55; re: teaching positions; big business, big labor, politics, writings, programs, etc.
SIMPSON, Albert (16), 1935-53; re: farmer's situation in 1935; Pillars of Agrarianism, teaching positions, dissertation, SHA meeting in Charleston, Presidential address, Georgia history, work at Maxwell field; World War II, work with Historical Division, Army Air Force; Negro problems.
STEPHENSON, Wendell H. (l4), 1935-53; re; book reviews for Journal of Southern History; articles for publication; teaching techniques; dissertations
STEWART, Edward Day (8), 1935-37; re: farm tenancy, agrarianism, and articles in American Review.
STONE, Geoffrey (4), 1936-51; re: The Examiner, and the lack of a periodical representing the point of view of the American conservative.
SWINT, Henry Lee (33); 1933-56; re: graduate work, army service, segregation and integration, teaching positions, politics, etc.
SYDNOR, Charles S. (9); 1937-50; re: SHA, recommendation to Social Science Research Council, historical writings on southern yeomen, and appreciation for review.
TATE, Allen (22), 1928-55; re: Who Owns America; agrarians, writings, Negro problem, speech at U. of A., etc.
VANCE, Rupert B., 1935; re: agrarianism.
WADE, John Donald (13); 1934-47; re: speech at University of Georgia, Georgia Review
WALTERS, Bennett (26), 1946-56; re: research, dissertation, W. T. Sherman, Emory and Henry, teaching positions, Vanderbilt, Alabama, Negroes, etc.
WARREN, Robert Penn (43), 1933-55; re: writings for Southern Review, literary criticism, poetry, etc.
WEAVER, Herbert (27); 1941-54; re: dissertation, armed services, land tenure studies attacked, publication of Mississippi Farmers, Air Force Historical Division
WINTERS, Curtis R. (2), 1933; re: The Third Crusade and I'II Take My Stand, sectionalism.
YOUNG, Stark (4), 1936; re: McGehees, selection of writings, etc.
FRANK OWSLEY PAPERS - CORRESPONDENCE, OUTGOING (index with notes by Harriet C. Owsley)
To Donald Davidson (8), 1927-52; re: agrarianism, poetry and other writings, communism, fascism, etc.
To John Gould Fletcher (5), 1933-35; re: agrarianism and the cause of the South, boycott of Virginia Quarterly Review (comments).
To Andrew Lytle (23), 1930-56; re: I'II Take My Stand, The Long Night, and other writings.
To Allen Tate (15), 1932-55; re: Who Owns America, teaching positions, agrarianism, etc.
To Robert Penn Warren (10), 1943-50; re: poetry and other writings, agrarianism writings for American Review. teaching positions, comments on various novels, balanced economy, characterizations of several old friends.
84 copies of outgoing letters of Frank Owsley for the inclusive dates 1932- 1956. A very fine letter to Chancellor Kirkland dated Jan. 8, 1935. These letters are only a few of which copies were kept. Frank Owsley usually wrote long hand and did not make copies.
ADDENDUM TO THE FRANK OWSLEY PAPERS (Outgoing Correspondence)
To Beard, Charles A. (1) Oct. 12, 1940; re: research for an article on farm families
To BUFORD, JIM (1) 1952; re: thank you note (dinner)
To CLARK, JULIE ) (2) 1956; re: accomodations in Cambridge
To GAIMES, WILLIAM L. (3) 1956; re: Junior Fulbright Award applicant, duties at St. Johns, luncheon invitation
To OWSLEY, HARRIET (4) 1956; re: (post cards) first impressions in London, shopping, finding abundant records to research
To PETRIE, DR. GEORGE (7) 1917-1927; re: requests for recommendations and new about Vanderbilt (these letters are xeroxed)
To SECRETARY-U.S. EDUCATIONAL COMMISSION IN UNITED KINGDOM (1) 1956; re: questions upon recieving the Fulbright Award
To VAN AUKEN, SHELDON (1) 1956; re: discoveries concerning U.S. diplomacy in England and other countries
To WATT, MR. GEOFFREY (1) 1956; re: ship voyage to England and daughter's schooling
ADDENDUM TO FRANK OWSLEY PAPERS (Outgoing Correspondence)
To Gower, Herschel (4) Oct. 18, 1955; re: Fulbright Award, Oct. 25, 1955; re: Fulbright Award, Nov. 4, 1955; re: Fulbright Award and project Battle for Survival: The American Civil War in Europe, Apr. 27, 1956; re: accomodations in Cambridge, Fugitive reunion, Oct. 30, 1956; from William Gaines re: death of Frank Owsley
To Owsley, Gordon (26) (these letters are xeroxed) [1927-28 ]; April 15, 1929; March 18, 1940; November 29, 1940; February 24, 1941; May 8, 1941; May 15, 1941; June 23, 1941; September 19, 1942; February 1, 1944; March 21, 1944; April 14 [1944 ] (incomplete); February 16, 1948; May 4, 1950; September 6, 1950; September 24, 1950; February 15, 1952; July 12, 1953 (incomplete?); October 31, 1953; February 14, 1954; April 16, 1954; May 2, 1954; November 30, 1954; January 15, 1955; n.d.; August 18, 1956.
FRANK OWSLEY PAPERS -- CORRESPONDENCE, INCOMING (index with notes by Harriet C. Owsley)
Figure in parentheses immediately following name denotes the number of letters if more than one. The dates are the inclusive dates of the letters. Asterisk indicates letters of particular interest and value.
*Abernethy, Thomas Perkins (12), 1933-53; Professor of History, University of Virginia; comments on writings of agrarians and Owsley's historical writings.
Adams, Homer J., 1953; re: thesis on anecdotal materials.
Agar, Herbert (4), 1935-36; re: plans for Who Owns America with enclosures of Ferris Greenslet (Houghton Mifflin Company) and Chard Powers Smith (who praises Land of the Free).
Akens, David and Helen (2), 1954; students expressing appreciation.
Alderson, William T. (5), 1945-54; re: dissertation and book reviews.
*Alexander, Thomas B. (39), 1942-56. These are good letters full of descriptions of England during and after V.E. day, opinions on politics and burning issues of the period. Anyone interested in World War II would find them valuable. Alexander was a naval officer. Other letters were written from places where he taught, including Clemson Agricultural College, Clemson, S.C., and Georgia Teachers College, Collegeboro, Ga. He discusses writings and teaching problems. He received a Guggenheim Fellowship in 1955.
Allen, James L., 1932; re: a note paid.
Andrews, Charles M., 1927; re: article on "Defeatism in Confederacy."
Andrews, Matthew Page (4), 1933-34; re: Simon Baruch Prize won by Owsley's student, S. B. Thompson.
Ander, O. Fritiof (4), 1951; re: Bureau of Census.
Applewhite, Davis, 1944; former student back in service.
Atkinson, Littleton B. (3), 1949-53; re: possible position.
Ausfeld, Mrs. Wilhelmina C., 1953; re: Abner McGehee's will regarding gift of Bibles to his descendants by Alabama Bible Society.
Austin, Jessie, 1934; re: request for vote.
Avant, Will L. (2), 1949; re: room for Larry.
Bagby, Muriel Martin (Mrs. A. Paul), 1952; re: books of grandfather, T. H. Ball, on Clarke County and Creek War.
Bailey, Hugh (15), 1953-56; re: work on dissertation on John Williams Walker and other subjects.
Bailey, Kenneth K., 1949; re: teaching position.
Bailey, Thomas A. (2), 1938, 1954; re: reading chapters of his Diplomatic History.
*Bankhead, J. H. (2), 1935; re: "Pillars of Agrarianism" and proposed Bill to create farm tenant homes. Enclosed is a radio talk by Senator Bankhead on the subject.
Barnes, Barbara Sue (3), 1951-52; re: Civil War history.
Barnes, J. Ward (21), 1941-54; re: school work, politics, and a speech to Southern Illinois Historical Society.
Barnhart, John D., 1945, re: historical writings.
Barton, B. W., 1945; re: growing kudzu.
Baylen, Joseph O. (2), 1956; re: teaching position.
*Beach, Leonard B. (2), 1954-55, re: collecting papers of Fugitives and Agrarians; also Waller project.
Beale, Howard K., 1940; re: program for SHA at AHA in New York.
*Beard, Charles A. (6), 1940-45; re: Plain Folk of Old South; states that his family were of that class; compliments work on a neglected field of American history.
Beard, William E., 1949; re: meeting of Tennessee Historical Commission.
*Beatty, Richmond C. (4), 1934-50; re: ms. of Bayard Taylor - if published, "it will just step up to you and call you Pappy"; compliments Plain Folk, especially chapter on Southern Folkways.
Benedict, A. B., 1951, re: friends at Vanderbilt who miss Owsley.